Brian Kim (Dong Hyun)

Irvine, CA 92602 (949) 285-1898 brian@bdhk.dev

linkedin.com/in/bdhk github.com/briandhkim bdhk.dev

Summary

Full-stack web developer with nearly six years of experience, skilled not only in technical disciplines but also in collaborating with diverse teams, including developers, QAs, business analysts, and client success managers. Experienced in resolving complex issues and delivering effective solutions.

Technical Skills

Languages:

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Ruby

Frameworks, libraries, & database:

Laravel, jQuery, Vue.js, React, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Tools, methodologies, & other:

Git, GitHub, Docker, Herd, Postman, axe DevTools, Jira, Confluence, Bamboo, AWS Cloud, Heroku, New Relic, Scrum, Kanban, Agile, accessible web development (WCAG), Test Driven Development (TDD)

Experience

Sr. Software Engineer | BeSmartee | Jul. 2021 - Apr. 2024

Engineering Team | Feb. 2023 - Apr 2024

- Created proof-of-concept (POC) applications for the company's V2 initiatives using new technology stack: React,
 Next.js, Laravel, and PostgreSQL
- Led the investigation and resolution of a critical data loss incident, delivering a **root cause analysis (RCA)** and successfully recovering 100% of the missing documents from the AWS server backup
- Spearheaded internal tools development, reducing redundant tasks for multiple stakeholders and increasing workflow efficiency by 99%
- Diagnosed optimization opportunities in the legacy PHP codebase and implemented refactored solutions, reducing runtime for some long-running scripts from minutes to milliseconds
- Mentored developers as well as members outside of engineering department to strengthen interdepartmental rapport *Service Team* | Jul. 2022 Feb. 2023
 - Engineered new microservices utilizing test-driven development (TDD) across two different technology stacks:
 Laravel and Ruby on Rails
 - Reinforced development using SOLID and DRY principles

PDT, Deployment Specialist | Jul. 2021 - Jul. 2022

- Supervised application deployments to the AWS Cloud via Bamboo
- Oversaw major version releases by assessing risks and identifying failure points, preventing issues from impacting production services

 Created deployment guidelines with safeguards, eliminating 100% of preventable defects and raising engineering standards

Software Engineer | BeSmartee | Feb. 2019 - Jul. 2021

Production Defect Team (PDT) | Oct. 2020 - Jul. 2021

- Triaged thousands of defect tickets to streamline incident resolution and resolved hundreds of urgent production-level issues, minimizing outages and ensuring business continuity
- Investigated a critical security breach, delivering a detailed root cause analysis (RCA) to stakeholders, which averted
 lawsuits and maintained key client relationships

Implementation Team | Feb. 2019 - Oct. 2020

- Orchestrated the upgrade of the encryption algorithm used by the existing PHP application, ensuring a seamless transition to stronger security standards
- Led frontend development of a new single-page application (SPA) using Vue.js and TailwindCSS with a focus on delivering a versatile user experience
- Developed applications with **Laravel** framework, enforcing **TDD** to create scalable codebase with zero reported bugs

Jr. Software Engineer | BeSmartee | Jul. 2018 - Feb. 2019

UX Team | Jul. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Enriched the existing jQuery frontend, implementing web accessibility improvements per Web Content
 Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG)

Education

University of California - Los Angeles (UCLA) | Bachelor of Arts: Psychology | 2016

Awards and Recognition

- 6th Person of the Year | BeSmartee | 2022
- *All Star Engineering* | BeSmartee | 2021
- Rookie of the Year | BeSmartee | 2018

References

Available upon request.